<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bazil</title>
    <link>https://bazil.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bazil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bazil.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Status update: a *distributed* filesystem</title>
      <link>https://bazil.org/2015/07/07/distributed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bazil.org/2015/07/07/distributed/</guid>
      <description>A lot of time has passed, and a lot of code has been written. Bazil is still in heavy development, but it has reached a good milestone to blog about: it can synchronize changes from one peer to another.
Warning: at this stage in development, we will put no effort into compatibility of file formats or protocols. Do not stare into laser with remaining eye.
What follows is a walkthrough of scenario where we have two computers sharing files &amp;ndash; find me at GopherCon for a live demo, or follow the steps and run it yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Bazil</title>
      <link>https://bazil.org/2014/04/24/introducing-bazil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bazil.org/2014/04/24/introducing-bazil/</guid>
      <description>GopherCon is here, and it is time to reveal what Bazil is all about.
Bazil, also known as bazil.org/bazil, is a file system that lets your data reside where it is most convenient for it to reside.
Bazil is still under heavy development, but welcomes developers and curious power users. Here&#39;s a little teaser of what&#39;s coming.
Imagine you have
  A laptop with a a 256GB SSD  A desktop with a 3TB hard disk  A cloud server or storage service (virtual machine with expandable disks, S3, etc) or  just a cheap computer in a closet with two slow 4TB disks or  external USB disk you plug in once a week for backups  On the desktop, you naturally want to be able to use the whole 3TB disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FUSE talk slides available</title>
      <link>https://bazil.org/2013/06/10/talk-about-fuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bazil.org/2013/06/10/talk-about-fuse/</guid>
      <description>Tv is talking about the Bazil FUSE library at the local Gopher meetup tonight. Check out the slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>https://bazil.org/2013/04/01/not-a-fool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bazil.org/2013/04/01/not-a-fool/</guid>
      <description>Hi. This blog post establishes the Bazil.org project. This is not an April Fool&#39;s joke.
There are more ambituous things floating in the background, but many people have expressed interest in this, so here&#39;s an early release: a Go FUSE filesystem programming library.
This is based on Russ Cox&amp;lsquo;s fuse library, as hosted at https://code.google.com/p/rsc/source/browse/#hg%2Ffuse
Here&#39;s how to get going:
go get bazil.org/fuse  The github repository is at https://github.com/bazil/fuse</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
